<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Embedded Kate Blog</title>
        <link>https://embeddedk8.com/</link>
        <description>I share my thoughts and in-depth articles on embedded systems, RTOS, and C programming — making complex topics easy to understand.</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>embeddedkate@gmail.com (embeddedk8)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>embeddedkate@gmail.com (embeddedk8)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:58:26 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://embeddedk8.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Arduino UNO R4 WiFi &#43; Arduino IoT Cloud: setup and firmware fix on Linux</title>
    <link>https://embeddedk8.com/arduino-iot-cloud/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:58:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>embeddedk8</author>
    <guid>https://embeddedk8.com/arduino-iot-cloud/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Getting your Arduino UNO R4 WiFi connected to Arduino IoT Cloud can be tricky on Linux. I describe the issue I encountered and how I fixed it.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Arduino Internals: building sketches with Arduino CLI</title>
    <link>https://embeddedk8.com/arduino-cli-compilation/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:58:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>embeddedk8</author>
    <guid>https://embeddedk8.com/arduino-cli-compilation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In the <a href="/arduino-ide-build-process/" rel="">previous post</a> we took a closer look at how the Arduino IDE builds sketches.
A lot happens behind the scenes — from the classic C/C++ build steps (preprocessing, compiling, assembling, and linking)
to a few Arduino-specific additions.</p>
<p>Now, let’s take things a step further and build the same project without the Arduino IDE — this time using the Arduino CLI (Arduino
Command Line Interface).</p>
<h1 id="compiling-arduino-sketch-via-arduino-cli">Compiling Arduino sketch via Arduino CLI</h1>
<p>It’s worth to start with mentioning that, starting with Arduino IDE 2.0, the Arduino IDE uses the Arduino CLI
for the build process. This means that when you build a sketch using the CLI directly, it follows exactly the same steps as the IDE does.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Arduino Internals: how Arduino IDE builds your code</title>
    <link>https://embeddedk8.com/arduino-ide-build-process/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 15:58:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>embeddedk8</author>
    <guid>https://embeddedk8.com/arduino-ide-build-process/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>As an embedded developer, you probably can&rsquo;t help wondering what actually happens when Arduino IDE builds the sketch.
What’s being compiled, where the files go, and how the toolchain turns the code into instructions able to run on the board?</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
